Guide to the Jesse Pyrant Andrews photographs and oral histories, 1973-2020 RL.00043
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Life at Large and Other Work, 1973-2020; 3.5 Linear Feet 54 prints; 4 CD-ROMs; 1.4 Gigabytes 4 audio files 2 .wav files; 2 .mp3 files
  - Front entrance, Mountain View plantation homeplace, Tightsqueeze, Virginia, 2019 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_250)
    I wrote extensive notes about my relationship with Mountain view and its owner in a previous submission to the archive.
  - Auction sale at Mountain View, 2019 September (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_251)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 175-36.
    The house and land, 164 acres, did not sell at this auction since no bid was offered that met the owner's reserve. The personal property and household furniture were sold that day. Stephen Burwell Law, who inherited Mountain View from his parents, left the property to his sister, Laura, who had not lived there since 1968. Laura had no interest in living there and so put it up for sale. The house and land were sold by a realtor in September, 2020. The new owners have vowed to maintain Mountain View as closely as possible to its original condition, according to the stipulation Steve put forth in the directive he left with his will. Steve had maintained it for years, making every effort to retain its historic integrity. He did not want Mountain View to fall into the hands of someone who would "modernize" the house by turning it into a bed and breakfast or a wedding venue. Laura did as he wished, and I know Steve would be glad that his wishes are being honored.
  - Mannequin with flags, 2018 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_252)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 83-29.
    This seemed an odd way to dress a mannequin a - strange attempt at patriotism or perhaps simply a whim. I didn't ask.
  - Jesse Pruitt at Fox's road house (Red Fox Inn), Pittsylvania County, Virginia, 1978 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_253)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 12-11.
    Fox's was originally owned by Floyd Fox, Jr., and his brother Bill Fox. They were sons of Floyd Fox, Sr., who also operated a road house (see print in Virginia series). The Red Fox inn was a local watering hole and meeting place for many years. Jesse Pruitt was an extraordinary pool player and usually "ran the table" on anyone willing to challenge him - meaning that his opponent almost never got a shot - his challenger in this image can be seen sitting to the left, waiting to lose and pay up. Jesse would clear the table and walk away with the wager.
  - Abandoned church, Halifax County, Virginia, 2018 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_254)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 146-34.
  - The old general store at the Ingram community, Halifax County, Virginia, 2019 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_255)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 140-33.
    A crossroads community, Ingram was once a thriving place, when tobacco was still the economic mainstay of the Old Belt region. This store was the center of the community's commercial activity, where just about anything was available - clothing, shoes, hardware, fresh meat and vegetables - whatever anyone might need. Credit was available, with no interest charged. If a farmer was cash poor, credit was extended until his crop sold in the Fall. The store was also a meeting place for the local residents to sit and play checkers and talk, or just visit and discuss the important topics of the day - weather, politics, who had the best-looking tobacco, who might need help with their crop. The loss of these community hubs has meant that in many places like Ingram, the people living there have grown less close and become busy with the mundane activities of more modern times - driving half an hour to buy what they could previously get at the general store, from people they don't know who work in businesses owned by people who are not local and only see customers as a source of profit.
  - Farm supply building, a part of the Ingram general store, Halifax County, Virginia, 2019 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_256)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 140-32.
    Where farm supplies were kept for sale at the general store. Anything a farmer might need, including blasting powder, was available.
  - Confederate statue during renovation of the Halifax County courthouse, 2020 (Box 16, Image RL00043_P_257)
    Orig. print number: JA/LAL 140-15.
    Here is the memorialized rebel, still overseeing the workers. During the summer of 2020 a petition was drawn up to remove the statue either altogether or move it to a more appropriate place, such as the county museum. Hundreds of local residents signed the petition, but the county board of supervisors passed the buck (after pleas from the "heritage not hate" contingent), deciding to place the issue on the ballot in the next county election. Meanwhile, the 20 million-dollar plus renovation of the 1838 structure continues.
- Original Media (closed to use), 64 cdrs 1 box
  75 original compact discs containing oral histories conducted by Jesse Andrews. Audio files have been migrated from the discs to a library server and are available upon advance request in the onsite Rubenstein Library reading room.
  The individual oral history recordings are listed with their corresponding interviewees in this collection guide.
  - Oral history CD-Rs, .2 Linear Feet f1 box 64 optical disks (Box 9)
    Original audio disks are closed to use; however, listening copies in digital file format are available on advance request. Please contact the Rubenstein Library for assistance.
  - Oral history CD-Rs, .2 Linear Feet 1 box 11 optical disks (Box 15)